Now, a sheet bend is another bend that we can put into a rope.
Once again, a bend is a rope that are not that you tie into a rope that is easy to untie, because most times when you put a knot in there you really can't untie them too well.
The problem with a sheet bend is that it does reduce the strength of the rope by fifty-five percent, or the strength of the line by fifty-five percent.
And it also not good though, if you have a sudden jerk, it will come loose.
So, just remember that whenever you're tying this one.
If you look down here at the table, you can see that I have a rope here, my blue line comes in, I've already made a loop in it here.
I'm just going to pull these two ropes together to make this loop a little more pizzazz.
And I'm going to take the working end of my red rope and it's going to go under, in here.
Then I?m going to take it over the outside line, like so.
And just loop it back under my loop, and over and through, like so.